Over three years ago, I quit
my job as a pentester for Bug
Bounty and creating content.
Unfortunately, the first two
years of Bug Bounty weren't as
easy as I expected them to be.
But last year, the 2024, I really
changed a lot, and I succeeded
at least by my standards.
In this video, I will tell you exactly
what I changed, what it takes to
succeed in Bug Bounty, and, as always,
I will share with you All the numbers.
Enjoy.
First a quick recap of my history.
If you want to see it in details, you
can watch the past bounty vlogs, but
I'll just quickly mention what happened.
In 2021,
I started hunting and I had
a few findings that year.
Then 2022, it looked
like a really good start.
I started hunting on more programs.
I had multiple bounties.
The year ended up with 21 paid bug
bounty reports totaling to about $24,000.
And I think it was a good start,
especially considering that year I
spent a lot of time on the business
side, on the channel side, because I
also had to basically learn everything.
But then it was 2023 and I
hoped to continue that trajectory.
But that year it was really bad.
if you watch the previous bounty vlog,
it didn't look as bad, but part of
it was because it didn't cover the
calendar year of 2023, but the period
that also had some bugs from 2022.
But if we look at 2023 itself, I only
had five paid bug bounty reports.
And yes, one of them was paid $20,000
so it didn't look as bad, but five
bug bounty reports in the whole year.
Yes, it was a difficult year for me
personally, but five, what was I doing?
I don't know, to be
honest, how it happened.
And myself, I was
surprised with this number.
So you can definitely see that.
It wasn't an easy start for me.
I am not a story of somebody who
just started bug bounty and started
finding bugs easily left and right.
But I was very, motivated
to eventually succeed.
I was learning new things all the
time, changing my approach, and
I think I finally got better.
And I'm in a point where I'm
really, happy with how it went.
the biggest change I've made in 2024 was
being an expert in one area of hacking.
Because if at the end of 2023,
you would ask me, what is my
strongest area of hacking?
I would tell you I'm good at everything,
which is a nice way of saying there was no
area at which I was exceptionally good at.
In 2024,
I spent a lot of time on authentication.
And if we take a look at stats out of 41
paid background reports in 2024, as much
as 14 are account takeovers totaling
to over $55,000, And some of them
are typical redirect_uri oauth ATOs.
There is one xss that I exploited as
an account takeover, but there's also
a lot of random bugs that don't even
have the name that were just very
specific to a particular functionality.
And they are not a result of me
copy pasting somebody's methodology.
It's just a result of me spending
time on auditing, probably
hundreds of authentication flows.
On implementing authentication
flows myself tens of times and just
understanding each piece of it.
And That's something I'm probably
the most proud of that this year.
I not only executed attacks that
I've learned from other people,
but also I had the chance to take
some ideas that I've had in the
past and I thought they can work.
And that year I proved
that they indeed work.
And some of them I
documented in the archive.
Feel free to to check them out and
I'm definitely going to continue
in 2025 focusing on authentication.
I really enjoy hacking this
part of applications.
I think the impact is great.
and the payouts itself, I think 55K
for 14 reports is a very, good result.
Quantity wise, my second most commonly
rewarded bug class in 2024 was
privilege escalation bugs, which I
wouldn't say is a part of my style.
And even though I had 13 reports, which
is only one less than the ATOs I mentioned
before with privilege escalations
out of out of 13 reports, I
didn't even make 10 grand.
So you see the average
bounty is way lower.
And the reality is out of these 13
reports, three are just my preparation for
recording the interview with the privilege
escalation God named Douglas Day.
And just when preparing for this
interview, I found a few myself.
And then I had one day where I reported
seven in a single application and
there were a few others as well.
So even though quantity wise,
there is, it's a big part.
I wouldn't say that's a
good part of my methodology.
I think there is a lot of privilege
escalations out there, but I wouldn't
say I'm especially good at it.
And I wouldn't say I want to be good at it
because the thing is, I don't really enjoy
looking for privilege escalation bugs.
And that's also one thing that I
learned last year that when you work
for yourself, like you do in Bug
Bounty, enjoyment of doing something.
Is not only for the sake of enjoying
it, but it's also for the sake of
keeping you motivated because when
you have no boss, if you have no
motivation, you will just not work.
You will just not put the time
which is essential in bug bounty.
I think it's the most important
aspect of bug bounty is as simple
as just putting in the time.
So I am not planning to focus
more on this bug class myself.
However, in 2025, I would
like to start using some hack
bots, maybe written by myself.
And I think privileged escalation
bugs would be something that I
would start with for to outsource
this to, to some AI hack bots.
Cause I think it should be fairly easy.
And I think there is a lot of
money on the table because I
know these bugs are everywhere.
And it just, the matter of.
sending enough requests to see them.
So hopefully I will start looking
for privilege escalations, but
not spending the time myself, just
having the, hackbots do it for me.
So if you look income wise, my
second most profitable bug class
this year were client side RCEs.
Even though I only had three paid
reports in this bug class, it yielded
at me over $17,000 And I really enjoyed
looking for these bugs, although.
To
look for them, you must have a
kind of specific functionality.
So even though I like them and I'm going
to keep looking for them whenever I
can, I would not say it's going to be
a big part of my methodology
because it is very specific.
So either this target can be
susceptible to this or not.
So I wouldn't say that's something that
I'm going to focus on a lot next year.
Maybe if I would, it would be more in
terms of target selection rather than
the actual hacking style in terms of
hacking style sort of the rest of the
bugs i've had There was a lot of I
would say infrastructure related bugs.
So ssrfs, traversals, request
smuggling these bugs I have
to say, I really like them.
And I think I should focus
more on them because I just
enjoy looking for these bugs.
I think I could automate
some of the checks.
Maybe I should look for some zero days.
And, also the impact of this bug is great.
And this is my, resolution
for this year as well.
Of course, I will
keep authentication
as my main bug class and I'm gonna
keep this as my priority, but then I
think I would like to spend more time
on these infrastructure related bugs.
And this is definitely something that
I want to spend more time in 2025.
In 2024, I also finally had some
opportunities to hack in the real world
and meet so many people in person.
First, I became the HackerOne
ambassador for Poland and we took
part in the HackerOne World Cup.
And in 2024, we advanced easily
through the elimination stage.
We advanced from the group stage.
We won the elite 16 round.
And personally I also had pretty good
rounds because in each of them I was
able to find highs or crits which
is a good achievement considering at
the first rounds you compete with 700
hunters and there is no dupe window so I
think I'm quite happy with the progress.
I also am very happy to
see Poland team succeed.
I think before this, we
didn't have the community.
So it's really nice to see how many
cool bugs we found during this round.
But then individually, I also
had the chance to participate in
two HackerOne life hacking events
in Las Vegas and in Edinburgh.
And it was amazing because
I met so many people that
I've known for years, but only from
the internet, only from online.
And it was great to speak with them
also findings wise, also both LHEs I
had highs, but even better in Edinburgh,
I was chosen for the show and tell for
those of you who don't know, show and tell
is the presentation at the life hacking
event where the customer chooses the most
interesting bugs to be shown on stage.
imagine me seeing so many people in
the room that I just looked up to as
my authorities and they all listened to
me explaining my back from the stage.
It was truly incredible
feeling and probably one of
my favorite moments of 2024.
So it was really, nice.
And just by hanging out with the top
hunters in the world, you simply absorb
the knowledge from everyone by just
talking with them and you understand
better and better what it actually
takes to succeed in bug bounty.
I would say for me that the biggest lesson
is that at this level, everyone has a
very, good technical knowledge, but it's
finding the applications.
That's the hard part.
Sometimes it's just doing good
recon, but other times everyone
knows the application, but one
person, maybe they bought the
subscription and bypassed the paywall.
Maybe they just figured out
better how to use certain feature.
Maybe they got verified and they have
access to endpoints that nobody else has.
Or sometimes, it's just out there
and nobody focuses on it because
they assume it is not insecure.
So this is the biggest lesson for me.
It's a very good way to put it is how
Douglas wrote it in his blog post.
Finding bugs is easy,
finding scope is hard.
For me, this one of the biggest
lessons of this year as well,
because I see from my bugs as well.
In the past two years, I had the
technical knowledge to find most of them.
But still I didn't.
And the reason was putting in
the time and just being in the
correct place at the correct time.
So maybe that's the case for you as well.
Maybe you do already have the technical
knowledge to find bugs in bug bounty
and the only thing you need is the
persistence and going through enough
programs, going through enough websites
and going through enough endpoints
Here comes the moment
you've all been waiting for.
The numbers.
First, for reference, here
we have the numbers from
Past two years and the total of my
bounties for 2024 is $96,347 and 67 cents.
I still have some mediations open,
and I hope I will actually cross the
$100k line, but even if I didn't,
I'm
really happy with this number, especially
that it's only part of my income.
I spend about three days
per week on average hacking.
So I know if I would focus 100 percent
of my time, I could easily cross the
100 K line and maybe even, higher.
So I decided to put this in the
title, even though technically, at
least for this moment, it's not true.
If you think I'm an idiot for doing
this, leave the comment down below.
If you think I'm not and you
enjoyed this video, also, I'm
waiting for all your comments.
For now,
thank you so much for
watching and goodbye!